<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Musings on Rick Gilmore&#39;s site</title>
    <link>/categories/musings/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Musings on Rick Gilmore&#39;s site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/musings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Humble gratitude</title>
      <link>/2016/11/24/humble-gratitude/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/11/24/humble-gratitude/</guid>
      <description>I am supposed to be thankful. Gratitude comes easily to me, and this holiday was always my favorite growing up.
But this Thanksgiving day I am reminded of native peoples, the first immigrants to this land, and the holocaust my ancestors&amp;rsquo; arrival brought upon them. We took their land, pillaged and murdered them, and then imprisoned the generations who survived in jails without walls. These truths are known, but too often forgotten.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preserve, protect, and defend</title>
      <link>/2016/11/22/preserve-protect-and-defend/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/11/22/preserve-protect-and-defend/</guid>
      <description>I got into an argument with my father two years ago over a blog post I wrote in the midst of an epidemic of police killings of unarmed black men. The recent events at Standing Rock, where my daughter Deb and her friends currently reside, have bearing on our disagreement.
My dad believes that civilians should obey police orders, and that those who do not put themselves at grave risk. I agree that disobeying police orders can put civilians in jeopardy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My plan</title>
      <link>/2016/11/15/my-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/11/15/my-plan/</guid>
      <description>I disagree with President-elect Trump on many matters of style and substance, but I agree with him that America needs to tackle a number of long-standing problems. In the spirit of constructive criticism, I offer a simple plan that I think will restore balance to our economic system while spurring growth and creating jobs.
It&amp;rsquo;s based on a simple principle: Everybody pays. No person who lives in this country and no business that operates here should avoid paying federal income tax.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Others&#39; thoughts</title>
      <link>/2016/11/14/others-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/11/14/others-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>Farewell, America by Neil Gabler.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back in the U.S.S.R.</title>
      <link>/2016/11/13/back-in-the-u-s-s-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/11/13/back-in-the-u-s-s-r/</guid>
      <description>When I was a Republican about 20 years ago, it was an article of faith that my party defended American interests abroad in an assertive way. I grew up in the Cold War when the U.S.S.R was our adversary, baiting us at every turn and in every geopolitical corner. NATO was our bulwark in Europe against Soviet expansion, but we waged proxy wars everywhere. When I played a crude geopolitical role playing game on my first ever Macintosh, my refusal to accede to simulated Soviet provocations inevitably resulted in game-ending nuclear conflict.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life is just a party</title>
      <link>/2016/11/11/life-is-just-a-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/11/11/life-is-just-a-party/</guid>
      <description>Enough voters in enough states voted for Donald Trump to elect him to the most powerful position on the planet. Why? Voters wanted change. Or, so they told pollsters.
Drain the swamp, Trump supporters said.
But, the same voters returned a Republican Congress to power. The same Congress that collects fat paychecks from taxpayers while doing nothing. The same Congress that passes no laws and confirms no Supreme Court justices. The same Congress that voters tell pollsters they hate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>These unbridled states of aggression</title>
      <link>/2016/11/08/these-unbridled-states-of-aggression/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/11/08/these-unbridled-states-of-aggression/</guid>
      <description>Tomorrow, I won&amp;rsquo;t be threatening people whose political views I oppose with violence or jail. I won&amp;rsquo;t be saying the election is rigged. I won&amp;rsquo;t be speculating about the next civil war while celebrating with friends and neighbors in a house of worship. I won&amp;rsquo;t suppress the rights of other people to exercise their right to vote. And, I won&amp;rsquo;t wear t-shirts threatening to lynch journalists.
There are countries where political opponents kill or jail one another, where elections are rigged, where civil wars rage and innocents die, where the right to vote is absent, and where journalists perish seeking out truth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Must we fight the Civil War again?</title>
      <link>/2016/07/08/must-we-fight-the-civil-war-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/07/08/must-we-fight-the-civil-war-again/</guid>
      <description>Must we fight the Civil War again?
That is the fundamental question that this hour of history poses for us to answer.
That is the question raised by the continued popularity of the Confederate flag and the reverence shown to it.
That is the question raised when the people&amp;rsquo;s armed representatives, officers of the peace, kill brown people again and again and again and again without punishment.
That is the question when neighbors, friends, and loved ones are slaughtered merely because they love differently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For good</title>
      <link>/2015/07/19/for-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/07/19/for-good/</guid>
      <description>Just before the curtain, I got the first hint. That was not a hay fever sneeze. The pharmacy was still open when I got to Euston Station after the show. I stocked up on cold remedies and went to check the departure track for the overnight to Edinburgh. Cancelled, the board said. I joined the queue at the customer service window. I could rebook on the first morning departure, but I&amp;rsquo;d miss my bus to the Western Highlands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liberty and justice for some</title>
      <link>/2014/12/08/liberty-and-justice-for-some/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/12/08/liberty-and-justice-for-some/</guid>
      <description>Like many of you, I&amp;rsquo;ve been heartsick at the recent stream of news about fatal encounters between unarmed black males and law enforcement. Heartsick because I still believe in the ideals our Founders strove to make real &amp;ndash; that it is self-evident, and therefore unarguable, that all people are created equal and endowed with inalienable rights that include life, and liberty, and the pursuit of happiness. I am heartsick because we have so badly strayed from these ideals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We don&#39;t need another hero</title>
      <link>/2014/11/24/we-don-t-need-another-hero/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/11/24/we-don-t-need-another-hero/</guid>
      <description>My wife and I watched Amir Bar-Lev&amp;rsquo;s documentary, &amp;ldquo;Happy Valley&amp;rdquo; over the weekend. Our mutual reaction at the end of the movie was to note what a sad, sad story it tells. It was a familiar story, one we lived through. And, while much of the material was familiar, some of it was not.
We live close to campus &amp;ndash; on game day, we can hear the stadium roar when the Nittany Lions score.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>