<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Teaching on Rick Gilmore&#39;s site</title>
    <link>/categories/teaching/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Teaching on Rick Gilmore&#39;s site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/teaching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Open teaching with RMarkdown and GitHub -- Complaints</title>
      <link>/2015/10/11/open-teaching-with-rmarkdown-and-github-complaints/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/10/11/open-teaching-with-rmarkdown-and-github-complaints/</guid>
      <description>In my last post, I sketched out my workflow for using RStudio&amp;rsquo;s RMarkdown package to make HTML-based slides that I serve via GitHub and the RawGit service. I&amp;rsquo;m still a fan, but there is trouble in paradise. Or, I should say that it&amp;rsquo;s not yet paradise. So, in this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll describe some of my complaints. My mom always used to chide me &amp;ldquo;if you don&amp;rsquo;t have something nice to say, don&amp;rsquo;t talk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open teaching with R Markdown and GitHub</title>
      <link>/2015/10/09/open-teaching-with-r-markdown-and-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/10/09/open-teaching-with-r-markdown-and-github/</guid>
      <description>In keeping with my effort to move my research toward more open and reproducible practices, I decided to build all of my lecture slides in RMarkdown using RStudio, make my syllabus and assignments in Markdown, and generate exams and quizzes using LaTex and its Exam class. The lecture slide workflow involves several steps:
 Making slides in RStudio. Exporting them to HTML. Editing the syllabus file to add links to the HTML, RMarkdown, and sometimes PDF versions of the slides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-lingual, after a fashion</title>
      <link>/2015/07/22/multi-lingual-after-a-fashion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/07/22/multi-lingual-after-a-fashion/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m giving a talk at the International Conference on Development and Learning/Epigenetic Robotics meeting in Providence in a few weeks. The talk offered me the chance to put into practice some of the software tools I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to master. The goal was to create a presentation that used open source software components, version control, and included the actual code used to generate as many of the figures as possible. You can see the talk draft at http://gilmore-lab.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>