<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Rick Gilmore&#39;s site</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Rick Gilmore&#39;s site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Choosing not to see</title>
      <link>/2017/06/05/choosing-not-to-see/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/05/choosing-not-to-see/</guid>
      <description>One of my fellow ham radio operators wryly thanked Al Gore for yesterday&amp;rsquo;s unusually code and wet weather.
Setting aside climate politics for a moment, let&amp;rsquo;s look at the data. See the big blue bar centered on June? It&amp;rsquo;s typically our rainiest month. I have to remind myself of this every one of the 20 odd years we&amp;rsquo;ve lived here. Junes are rainy. Get over it. The average lows and highs are 59 deg and 78 deg, respectfully.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The whole elephant</title>
      <link>/2017/06/05/the-whole-elephant/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/05/the-whole-elephant/</guid>
      <description>A couple of months ago, I was feeling rather cranky about the state of our political union. Still am, truth be told. At that time the working title of this piece was &amp;ldquo;Making psychology great.&amp;rdquo; But the current title better reflects the spirit I hoped to capture. Psychology is already great and wonderful in so many ways. I just want to see the whole elephant, don&amp;rsquo;t you? So, here&amp;rsquo;s my manifesto.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogdown workflow</title>
      <link>/2017/06/04/blogdown-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/04/blogdown-workflow/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve relaunched my blog after a long hiatus. The reboot gave me a chance to learn a new tool&amp;ndash;blogdown&amp;ndash;and it forced me to revisit some old posts from my former blog platform. I wrote a lot of poetry in the last couple of years, most of it sparked by various personal events. Not all of it sounds as good to me now as it did then, but I avoided the temptation to edit my past.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving to blogdown</title>
      <link>/2017/06/03/moving-to-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/03/moving-to-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to move my blog to the blogdown package. I spend so much of my research life in RStudio it makes sense to move this direction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who shall lionize</title>
      <link>/2017/03/17/who-shall-lionize/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/03/17/who-shall-lionize/</guid>
      <description>who shall lionize this deceased? and where pray tell shall the bodiless be interred? i know not where to lay bouquets nor what color on such civic holy-days that celebrate my dear departed.  the stones i have accumulated to mark a graveside visit stack cold
hurl them at the walls of this always glass but newly transparent house of cards. shatter or bounce. who cares?  when dreams die the pain sears as befits that without which we choose not to endure  but must.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>lipstick on a pig</title>
      <link>/2017/01/15/lipstick-on-a-pig/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/01/15/lipstick-on-a-pig/</guid>
      <description>some Wilburs inspire no spider-poets nor earn the love of Fern.
this pig shuns lipstick. his countenance admits no adornment.
ears perky, hairs erect, nose for mayhem acute, undulled, taste for anything.  Orwell&amp;rsquo;s Napoleon commands our farm. cowed, we animals howl or growl assent to each assertion of fat cat dogma.  Ham? I am. you speak newspeak? come wallow in the mud and muck with me. it&amp;rsquo;s warm; you&amp;rsquo;re welcome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>fear and loathing</title>
      <link>/2017/01/14/fear-and-loathing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/01/14/fear-and-loathing/</guid>
      <description>fear and loathing mouthparts foaming eyeballs rolling twitter trolling  heaven, hell who can tell prideful swell what&amp;rsquo;s that smell  red or blue false or true in a stew what to do  forward back email hack ceiling crack fiction fact  smaller words most absurd loins to gird anti-nerd  seek the sun american race not won work ain&amp;rsquo;t done</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Humble gratitude</title>
      <link>/2016/11/24/humble-gratitude/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/11/24/humble-gratitude/</guid>
      <description>I am supposed to be thankful. Gratitude comes easily to me, and this holiday was always my favorite growing up.
But this Thanksgiving day I am reminded of native peoples, the first immigrants to this land, and the holocaust my ancestors&amp;rsquo; arrival brought upon them. We took their land, pillaged and murdered them, and then imprisoned the generations who survived in jails without walls. These truths are known, but too often forgotten.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preserve, protect, and defend</title>
      <link>/2016/11/22/preserve-protect-and-defend/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/11/22/preserve-protect-and-defend/</guid>
      <description>I got into an argument with my father two years ago over a blog post I wrote in the midst of an epidemic of police killings of unarmed black men. The recent events at Standing Rock, where my daughter Deb and her friends currently reside, have bearing on our disagreement.
My dad believes that civilians should obey police orders, and that those who do not put themselves at grave risk. I agree that disobeying police orders can put civilians in jeopardy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My plan</title>
      <link>/2016/11/15/my-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/11/15/my-plan/</guid>
      <description>I disagree with President-elect Trump on many matters of style and substance, but I agree with him that America needs to tackle a number of long-standing problems. In the spirit of constructive criticism, I offer a simple plan that I think will restore balance to our economic system while spurring growth and creating jobs.
It&amp;rsquo;s based on a simple principle: Everybody pays. No person who lives in this country and no business that operates here should avoid paying federal income tax.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Others&#39; thoughts</title>
      <link>/2016/11/14/others-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/11/14/others-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>Farewell, America by Neil Gabler.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back in the U.S.S.R.</title>
      <link>/2016/11/13/back-in-the-u-s-s-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/11/13/back-in-the-u-s-s-r/</guid>
      <description>When I was a Republican about 20 years ago, it was an article of faith that my party defended American interests abroad in an assertive way. I grew up in the Cold War when the U.S.S.R was our adversary, baiting us at every turn and in every geopolitical corner. NATO was our bulwark in Europe against Soviet expansion, but we waged proxy wars everywhere. When I played a crude geopolitical role playing game on my first ever Macintosh, my refusal to accede to simulated Soviet provocations inevitably resulted in game-ending nuclear conflict.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life is just a party</title>
      <link>/2016/11/11/life-is-just-a-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/11/11/life-is-just-a-party/</guid>
      <description>Enough voters in enough states voted for Donald Trump to elect him to the most powerful position on the planet. Why? Voters wanted change. Or, so they told pollsters.
Drain the swamp, Trump supporters said.
But, the same voters returned a Republican Congress to power. The same Congress that collects fat paychecks from taxpayers while doing nothing. The same Congress that passes no laws and confirms no Supreme Court justices. The same Congress that voters tell pollsters they hate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>These unbridled states of aggression</title>
      <link>/2016/11/08/these-unbridled-states-of-aggression/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/11/08/these-unbridled-states-of-aggression/</guid>
      <description>Tomorrow, I won&amp;rsquo;t be threatening people whose political views I oppose with violence or jail. I won&amp;rsquo;t be saying the election is rigged. I won&amp;rsquo;t be speculating about the next civil war while celebrating with friends and neighbors in a house of worship. I won&amp;rsquo;t suppress the rights of other people to exercise their right to vote. And, I won&amp;rsquo;t wear t-shirts threatening to lynch journalists.
There are countries where political opponents kill or jail one another, where elections are rigged, where civil wars rage and innocents die, where the right to vote is absent, and where journalists perish seeking out truth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoo-ology</title>
      <link>/2016/10/28/zoo-ology/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/10/28/zoo-ology/</guid>
      <description>there&#39;s an elephant in this room. i like them, usually, but this one has her trunk in my…
you don&#39;t see it? but, there&#39;s hardly room to breathe, and then of course the smell. be careful where you step.
i don&#39;t know how it got here. they start small like everything else. slip in your back pocket or  through the eye of the needle blindly following some stupid camel or  summoned by incantations like this unsaid that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the air</title>
      <link>/2016/07/22/on-the-air/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/07/22/on-the-air/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to be an amateur radio operator since I was a little kid and read about the hobby in Boys&amp;rsquo; Life magazine. As a high schooler, I scraped together the pennies to buy a shortwave radio receiver, a Yaesu FRG-7, and with a long wire I ran up to the roof of my parents&amp;rsquo; house, I listened to the world. Catching the English language broadcast of Radio Tirana from Albania was a memorable highlight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Must we fight the Civil War again?</title>
      <link>/2016/07/08/must-we-fight-the-civil-war-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/07/08/must-we-fight-the-civil-war-again/</guid>
      <description>Must we fight the Civil War again?
That is the fundamental question that this hour of history poses for us to answer.
That is the question raised by the continued popularity of the Confederate flag and the reverence shown to it.
That is the question raised when the people&amp;rsquo;s armed representatives, officers of the peace, kill brown people again and again and again and again without punishment.
That is the question when neighbors, friends, and loved ones are slaughtered merely because they love differently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>expiation</title>
      <link>/2016/05/12/expiation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/05/12/expiation/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>promise</title>
      <link>/2016/02/25/promise/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/02/25/promise/</guid>
      <description>I flare my talons and prepare to strike, but only in defense. I sharpen my beak, but only in warning.
I am your presidential detail, your Secret Service. Vigilant. Committed. I seek out bullets fired in your direction by indifferent snipers and absorb their impact with joy. Unwounded.
I will carry your heart when it cannot be lifted. I will find you when you are lost even to yourself. I will light your darkness with the fire in my eyes, and we will crawl together out of the wilderness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>delightful delusion</title>
      <link>/2016/02/20/delightful-delusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/02/20/delightful-delusion/</guid>
      <description>oh my, yes. I oh so wanted to see a tuxedo, penguin crisp, satin shiny, pseudo-sparkle when he sauntered by us peons, clinging to such rags as misfortune left in her cloud of dust and tears. Coughing.
but, oh my no. no. Clad there not in finery, but in the simplest of suits. Birthday I am told the style. Flattered, but not flattering. Scoffing, not coughing.
And in seeing I could not unsee, despite I swear so wanting, you must believe, Nor in knowing could I unknow what what wisdom bears in its stoop and beard the penultimate emptiness of every emperor, penguin or man.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>specific gravity</title>
      <link>/2016/01/21/specific-gravity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/01/21/specific-gravity/</guid>
      <description>the call always comes too early in the morning for anything but mischief or the baker
I know who&#39;s talking but not the language spoken.
hand on the bannister does not steady. the direction of gravity skewed by other forces of nature.
there now is down, but which way up?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open teaching with RMarkdown and GitHub -- Complaints</title>
      <link>/2015/10/11/open-teaching-with-rmarkdown-and-github-complaints/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/10/11/open-teaching-with-rmarkdown-and-github-complaints/</guid>
      <description>In my last post, I sketched out my workflow for using RStudio&amp;rsquo;s RMarkdown package to make HTML-based slides that I serve via GitHub and the RawGit service. I&amp;rsquo;m still a fan, but there is trouble in paradise. Or, I should say that it&amp;rsquo;s not yet paradise. So, in this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll describe some of my complaints. My mom always used to chide me &amp;ldquo;if you don&amp;rsquo;t have something nice to say, don&amp;rsquo;t talk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open teaching with R Markdown and GitHub</title>
      <link>/2015/10/09/open-teaching-with-r-markdown-and-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/10/09/open-teaching-with-r-markdown-and-github/</guid>
      <description>In keeping with my effort to move my research toward more open and reproducible practices, I decided to build all of my lecture slides in RMarkdown using RStudio, make my syllabus and assignments in Markdown, and generate exams and quizzes using LaTex and its Exam class. The lecture slide workflow involves several steps:
 Making slides in RStudio. Exporting them to HTML. Editing the syllabus file to add links to the HTML, RMarkdown, and sometimes PDF versions of the slides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i never metaphysis</title>
      <link>/2015/08/14/i-never-metaphysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/08/14/i-never-metaphysis/</guid>
      <description>it&#39;s like fireworks, dad. you said the colors and patterns come from all the minerals. their making a mutual arrangement designed to ignite and illuminate.  you said the designers crafted this one boomy blue and that one sparkly-white. this cascade brilliant, that smiley face a dud.  flying high or bursting low, it&#39;s all in the timing and atmospheric conditions. don&#39;t forget chemistry and physics. human ingenuity (and error).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-lingual, after a fashion</title>
      <link>/2015/07/22/multi-lingual-after-a-fashion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/07/22/multi-lingual-after-a-fashion/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m giving a talk at the International Conference on Development and Learning/Epigenetic Robotics meeting in Providence in a few weeks. The talk offered me the chance to put into practice some of the software tools I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to master. The goal was to create a presentation that used open source software components, version control, and included the actual code used to generate as many of the figures as possible. You can see the talk draft at http://gilmore-lab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>lonely cicada</title>
      <link>/2015/07/21/lonely-cicada/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/07/21/lonely-cicada/</guid>
      <description>Lonely cicada. Bad at math. Off by one? Damn. No choral singing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For good</title>
      <link>/2015/07/19/for-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/07/19/for-good/</guid>
      <description>Just before the curtain, I got the first hint. That was not a hay fever sneeze. The pharmacy was still open when I got to Euston Station after the show. I stocked up on cold remedies and went to check the departure track for the overnight to Edinburgh. Cancelled, the board said. I joined the queue at the customer service window. I could rebook on the first morning departure, but I&amp;rsquo;d miss my bus to the Western Highlands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>haiku 4 u</title>
      <link>/2015/07/12/haiku-4-u/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/07/12/haiku-4-u/</guid>
      <description>One last time, Dad says. Jason squeals ands bolts inside the mister. Slippery guy.
The audacity of giant metal tin-men shames the humbler heart.
What are crab cheese fries? Regular with seasoning? Do they sell? Who knows?
The didgery-dude took a raincheck. See, honey, I should have bought one.
Nittany Lion mating calls echo &amp;lsquo;cross the Borough. Love me, do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>food for thought</title>
      <link>/2015/05/07/food-for-thought/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/05/07/food-for-thought/</guid>
      <description>yes she cranked the handle but the meat and potato man put his heart in the grinder and no one saved the pink spaghetti strands for chili.
 he could have had his cake and eaten humble pie or worn it as a badge of honorable intent. instead he tasted just desserts that fate sandwiched between margaritaville and a cheeseburger in paradise.  full of gumption Forest&#39;s mother disparaged the integrity of chocolates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>barnyard diary</title>
      <link>/2015/03/06/barnyard-diary/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/03/06/barnyard-diary/</guid>
      <description>Feeling sheepish? You try wearing wool in July. Ya think I&amp;rsquo;d chew this stuff if I could smoke it?
Hey, lady, let me juice yours.
I&#39;m past waiting for some sweet-talking spider to say I&#39;m super. The horse is an ass. Aren&#39;t they all? I don&#39;t relish rooster&#39;s cock &#39;em who&#39;ll do any more than you two. You see, cherie, he crows he wants to do me. If I could sleep in a bed, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t roll in the hay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>four letter word</title>
      <link>/2015/03/06/four-letter-word/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/03/06/four-letter-word/</guid>
      <description>I strangled hope. Smug bastard annoyed me. I spring eternal; there is always room for me, he&#39;d say (or his fanboys would moonily recite). So I grabbed his throat and fingers clenched squeezed. his eyes bulged green then withered gray. he lay dishrag limp on my lap. I hissed a firehose sigh, a contrail marking passage across some cloudless sky and felt don&#39;t laugh full of...
Persistent bastard. Kill you again if I have the chance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>unsolicited advice</title>
      <link>/2015/01/12/unsolicited-advice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/01/12/unsolicited-advice/</guid>
      <description>My unicorn Is patron saint of regret. He holds dominion over Things wished-for but not received. the unfulfilled, unrequited, unrealized.
Get it? He says, I&#39;m like a Magritte or an Escher. Self-referential.
I don&#39;t. Or, I do, but I&#39;m wallowing.
Quite unselfservingly, He says I should shun the vaporous un.... and rather mind those things I got but did not think to wish for.
Treasure there, matey --  Forges to steel the metal in yer mettle; (He&#39;s fond of pirate talk, too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angels blue</title>
      <link>/2015/01/09/angels-blue/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/01/09/angels-blue/</guid>
      <description>Gods I&#39;ve always viewed with skepticism, But, I met an angel named Shirley.
They don&#39;t wear wings, you know. Impractical indoors. Hard to fit under a winter coat. Showy. Too many feathers ruffled already.
Or halos. Lord knows we have enough of those.
Sensible shoes? You bet. Got to keep their footing sure.
Craig or Suzanne might play a little trumpet, but only in the municipal band.
And none of them want to wrestle, ok?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liberty and justice for some</title>
      <link>/2014/12/08/liberty-and-justice-for-some/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/12/08/liberty-and-justice-for-some/</guid>
      <description>Like many of you, I&amp;rsquo;ve been heartsick at the recent stream of news about fatal encounters between unarmed black males and law enforcement. Heartsick because I still believe in the ideals our Founders strove to make real &amp;ndash; that it is self-evident, and therefore unarguable, that all people are created equal and endowed with inalienable rights that include life, and liberty, and the pursuit of happiness. I am heartsick because we have so badly strayed from these ideals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We don&#39;t need another hero</title>
      <link>/2014/11/24/we-don-t-need-another-hero/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/11/24/we-don-t-need-another-hero/</guid>
      <description>My wife and I watched Amir Bar-Lev&amp;rsquo;s documentary, &amp;ldquo;Happy Valley&amp;rdquo; over the weekend. Our mutual reaction at the end of the movie was to note what a sad, sad story it tells. It was a familiar story, one we lived through. And, while much of the material was familiar, some of it was not.
We live close to campus &amp;ndash; on game day, we can hear the stadium roar when the Nittany Lions score.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metadata? Whadja think?</title>
      <link>/2014/10/14/metadata-whadja-think/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/10/14/metadata-whadja-think/</guid>
      <description>Databrary has received generous funding from NSF and NICHD in order to foster increased data sharing and reuse. In the almost four years I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on the project, I&amp;rsquo;ve learned a great deal about data repositories and open and transparent research practices. One thing has consistently stood out: Successful repositories attract research communities around datasets when the data have useful and searchable metadata. It&amp;rsquo;s not enough to store and share materials and data openly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving the scientific enterprise</title>
      <link>/2014/09/23/improving-the-scientific-enterprise/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/09/23/improving-the-scientific-enterprise/</guid>
      <description>The White House Office of Science and Technology Policy has asked for information from the public about how best to maximize the benefits to the public stemming from investments in science and technology. Here are the brief comments I submitted.
I believe that the Federal government has a key role to play in ensuring that public investments in scientific research have the maximum benefit. I speak to these issues as the grateful recipient of Federal support for my research from the National Science Foundation and the National Institutes of Health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s get relational</title>
      <link>/2014/09/03/let-s-get-relational/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/09/03/let-s-get-relational/</guid>
      <description>We know that Databrary will have to compete against other data sharing services. Those of us who really enjoy building products and providing services that help others don&amp;rsquo;t like to talk about competing, but it&amp;rsquo;s a fact of life. Our project has generous support from NSF and NICHD now, but that&amp;rsquo;s no guarantee about the future of the project. We have to deliver a service that meets researcher&amp;rsquo;s needs. But, rather than worry about how Databrary can compete against Dropbox or Box or Amazon to provide cloud storage, we&amp;rsquo;re doing something else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Striking a balance</title>
      <link>/2014/09/01/striking-a-balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/09/01/striking-a-balance/</guid>
      <description>YouTube is a fantastic service. I use it all the time in my teaching. But, those of us working on Databrary find ourselves saying &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re not YouTube&amp;rdquo; on a regular basis. Here&amp;rsquo;s why.
Our core community consists of researchers who study infant and child development. We use video to collect the richest possible sample of behavior in natural or laboratory settings. Video often contains faces, voices, and names spoken aloud. This means that the videos could be used to determine the identity of research participants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>The whole elephant       code{white-space: pre;} pre:not([class]) { background-color: white; }  if (window.hljs &amp;&amp; document.readyState &amp;&amp; document.readyState === &#34;complete&#34;) { window.setTimeout(function() { hljs.initHighlighting(); }, 0); }  h1 { font-size: 34px; } h1.title { font-size: 38px; } h2 { font-size: 30px; } h3 { font-size: 24px; } h4 { font-size: 18px; } h5 { font-size: 16px; } h6 { font-size: 12px; } .table th:not([align]) { text-align: left; }    .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>